-You cannot pass! -Gandalf!
一你过不来 一鞭道夫
! ama servant of the Secret Fire, wielder of the flame of Anor.
我是圣灵的仆人 上帝的守护者
Go back to the Shadow.
滚回黑暗中去吧
The dark fire will not avail you, flame of Udiin!
你这那恶之火 恶魔也帮不了你
You shall not pass!
不 你休想过来
No! No!
不不
Gandalf!
甘道夫
Fly, you fools.
快光 傻瓜
No!
不
Gandalf!
甘道夫
What is it, Mr. Frodo?
你怎么了 佛罗多老爷
Just a dream.
我做了个梦
Mordor. The one place in Middle-earth we don't want to see any closer.
魔多 这个谁也不想去的地方
And it's the one place we're trying to get to.
也是我们不得不去的地方
It's just where we can't get.
可是我们又去不了那儿
Let's face it, Mr. Frodo, we're lost.
夯对现实吧 佛罗多老爷 我们迷路了
I don't think Gandalf meant for us to come this way.
我想这不是甘道夫 为我们安挂的路线
He didn't mean for a lot of things to happen, Sam...
有很多事情他没有安排 山姆
...but they did.
但却发生了
Mr. Frodo?
佛罗多老他
It's the Ring, isn't it?
是魔戒在作怪 对吗
It's getting heavier.
它越来越沉重
-What food have we got left? -Let me see.
一还有什么吃的吗 一我看看
Oh, yes. Lovely.
看哪 太好了
Lembas bread. And look!
精灵人饼干 再找找
More lembas bread.
还是精灵傍干
I don't usually hold with foreign food...
我一般不喜欢外国食品
...but this Elvish stuff, it's not bad.
不过这种供干的味道还不错
Nothing ever dampens your spirits, does it, Sam?
什么也不能让你消沉 对吗 山姆
Those rain clouds might.
除了下雨
This looks strangely familiar.
这个地方看着眼熟
It's because we've been here before.
因为我们来过这里
We're going in circles.
我们在和掀国子
What is that horrid stink?
有一股腐臭的气味
warrant there's a nasty bog nearby.
附近一定有烂泥塘
-Can you smell it? -Yes.
-你能闻到吗? -是的
l can smell it.
我闻到了
We're not alone.
这周围还有人
The filthy little thieves.
让人恶心的炭
Where is it?
在哪儿
They stole it from us.
被他们偷走了
My precious.
我的宝贝
Curse them, we hates them!
该死的 我恨他们
It's ours, itis, and we wants it!
那是我们的 我要夺回来
This is Sting.
这把宝剑
You've seen it before...
你曾经见过
... haven't you, Gollum?
对不对 咕噜
Release him or I'll cut your throat.
把他放开 不然的话我就要你的命
It burns!
汤 Ac
It burns us!
汤死我了
It freezes!
它一会源一会凉
Nasty Elves twisted it.
该死的精灵绳索
-Take it off us! -Quiet, you!
- 快把它给我拿掉 =- 住嘴
It's hopeless. Every Orc in Mordor's going to hear this racket.
这样不行 魔多的半兽人 会听到他的叫声
-Let's just tie him up and leave him. -No!
-干脆把他捆起来扔掉 -不
That would kill us! Kill us!
那样我就没命了 没命了
It's no more than you deserve!
都是你自找的
Maybe he does deserve to die.
尽管他罪该万死
But now that I see him, ! do pity him.
可他这样子很让人同情
We be nice to them if they be nice to us.
行善之人必有凌报
Take it off us.
快给我解开吧
We swears to do what you wants.
我一定俯首贴耳 我发誓
There's no promise you can make that I can trust.
你的话无论如何也不能让人相信
...to serve the master of the precious.
我会效忠宝物的主人
We will swear on...
我以魔戒的名义
Gollum. Gollum.
咕噜 咕噜
The Ring is treacherous. It will hold you to your word.
魔戒并不可信 不过我们会让你信守诺言的
Yes...
是的
...on the precious.
以魔戒的名义
I don't believe you!
我不相信你
-Get down! ! said, down! -Sam!
-下来 下来 -山姆
If we let him go, he'll throttle us in our sleep.
如果放他走 他会在夜里拘死我们的
-You know the way to Mordor? -Yes.
-你认识去魔多的路吗 -是的
You've been there before?
你去过那里吗
Yes.
是的
You will lead us to the Black Gate.
那你融我们去魔多之门
Merry!
梅里
What is it? What do you smell?
什么味? 你闻到了吗
Man-flesh.
是人类
Aragorn.
阿拉贡
They've picked up our trail.
他们发现了我们
Let's move!
快走
Their pace has quickened.
他们加快了速度
They must have caught our scent.
一定是闻到了气味
Hurry!
快
Come on, Gimli!
金勇 快点
Three days and nights pursuit.
我们追了三天三夜
No food. No rest.
不吃不喝
And no sign of our quarry, but what bare rock can tell.
除了梁迹连鬼影也没见到一个
Not idly do the leaves of Lérien fall.
这是故意丢在地上留给我们看的
They may yet be alive.
也许他们还活着
Less than a day ahead of us. Come.
只差一天距离了 我们得快点
Come, Gimli! We're gaining on them!
快点 金雳 就要追上他们了
I'm wasted on cross-country. We Dwarves are natural sprinters.
我不善于长途奔约 我们矮人善于短跑
Very dangerous over short distances.
要是短跑无人可比
Rohan.
罗罕国
Home of the Horse-lords.
骑士之乡
There's something strange at work here.
这里好像不大对头
Some evil gives speed to these creatures.
有某种强大的势力在驱赶着他们
Sets its will against us.
像是要与我们一争高下
Legolas! What do your Elf-eyes see?
莱戈拉斯 你看到了什么
The Uruks turn northeast.
他们去了东北方
They are taking the Hobbits to Isengard.
把堆比特人带到艾辛格去了
Saruman.
萨重曼
The world is changing.
世界正在改变
Who now has the strength to stand against the armies of Isengard...
现在谁还能对抗艾辛格
...and Mordor?
和魔多的军队?
To stand against the might of Sauron and Saruman...
对抗索伦和萨曾曼强权
...and the union of the two towers?
以及双塔联盟?
Together, my Lord Sauron...
索伦君王
...we shall rule this Middle-earth.
我们将共同统治中土世界
The Old World will burn in the fires of industry.
旧世界已在工业化的 火焰中化为灰蛤
The forests will fail.
森林将不复存在
A new order will rise.
新的秩序将会建立
We will drive the machine of war with the sword and the spear...
我们将用利剑 长矛和铁拳
...and the iron fists of the Ore.
来驱动战争的机器
We have only to remove those who oppose us.
谁敢对抗我们 将被赶尽杀绝
The Horse-Men took your lands.
罗军人侵占了你们的土地
They drove your people into the hills to scratch a living off rocks.
把你们赶进深山饱受胡熬
Murderers!
杀人犯
Take back the lands they stole from you.
把你们的土地收回来
Burn every village!
把村庄烧掉
It will begin in Rohan.
我们先从罗罕人开刀
Too long have these peasants stood against you.
他们一直都在反对你
But no more.
该结束了
. . Eothain! Eothain!
伊欧参 伊欧参
You take your sister. You'll go faster with just two.
你帝妹妹走吧 两个人跑得快一些
. Papa says Eothain must not ride Garulf.
爸爸不让伊欧参骑加重夫
He is too big for him.
它太高了
Listen to me. You must ride to Edoras and raise the alarm.
听妈妈的话 你们一定赶到伊多拉斯去报警
-Do you understand me? -Yes, Mama.
=-懂我的意思吗 -懂了 妈妈
I don't want to leave. 1 don't want to go, Mama.
我不要离开你 我不想走 妈妈
Freda, I will find you there.
斐代 我会去找你们
Quickly!
快走吧
Go, child.
逃命吧 孩子们
Rohan, my lord...
我的君王 罗罕
.. 48 ready fo fall.
就要到手了
Your son is badly wounded, my lord.
您的儿子伤势很重 国王
He was ambushed by Orcs.
他遭到半兽人效击
If we don't defend our country, Saruman will take it by force.
如果我们再不捍卫国家 萨鲁曼就要把它夺去了
That is a lie.
真是无稽之谈
Saruman the White has ever been our friend and ally.
自袍巫师萨重曼一贯是 我们的朋友和同盟
Orcs are roaming freely across our lands.
半兽人在我们的土地上无恶不作
Unchecked. Unchallenged. Killing at will.
他们肆无忌恒横行霸道滥杀无春
Orcs bearing the White Hand of Saruman.
头盔上都带有萨重曼的白手微章
Why do you lay these troubles on an already troubled mind?
为什么要给一颗不平静的心添堵
Can you not see?
看不出来吗
Your uncle is wearied by your malcontent...
你舅舅已经厌倦了你的不满情绪
. ... your warmongering.
和胡言乱语
Warmongering?
胡言乱语?
How long is it since Saruman bought you?
萨鲁曼什么时候收买了你
What was the promised price, Grima?
他给了你多少好处 葛力马
When all the Men are dead, you will take your share of the treasure?
等大家都死了 你就可以拿到赏金了?
Too long have you watched my sister.
你早就对我妹妹垂省三尺
Too long have you haunted her steps.
我不许你打她的主意
. . You see much, Eomer, son of Eomund.
你看到的太多了 伊欧墨 太多了
Too much.
从现在起
You are banished forthwith from the kingdom of Rohan...
你被罗罕王国放逐了
...under pain of death.
如果回来将被处死
Keep breathing. That's the key.
保持呼吸 就是胜利
Breathe.
呼吸
We're not going no further...
我们实在跑不动了
...Until we've had a breather.
我们现在需要休息
Get a fire going!
把得火点起来
Merry!
梅里
I think we might have made a mistake leaving the Shire, Pippin.
我想我们离开夏尔是个错误 皮平
What's making that noise?
梅里 是什么声音?
It's the trees.
是那些树
What?
什么
You remember the Old Forest, on the borders of Buckland?
还记得雄鹿地边境的那片老森林吗
Folk used to say there was something in the water that made the trees grow tall...
人们常说那儿的水 滋润着各种树木长大
...and come alive.
还给他们灵性
Alive?
灵性?
Trees that could whisper...
那些树会说话
...talk to each other...
彼此交谈
. even move.
还能走动
I'm starving.
我饿坏了
We ain't had nothing but maggoty bread for three stinking days.
三天来我们只吃过 一些发了老的破面包
Yeah!
是啊
What about them?
他们怎么样
They are not for eating.
不 听着 他们可不能吃
What about their legs?
光吃大腿行吗
They don't need those.
他们不需要腿
-They look tasty. -Get back, scum!
-一定很好吃 - 住手
No!
不行
Looks like meat's back on the menu, boys.
听着 半口也不行 伙计们
Pippin.
皮平
Let's go.
咱们走
Go on.
喊吧
Call for help.
快喊救命吧
Squeal.
大声点
No one's going to save you now.
这回没人来救你们
Pippin!
皮平
A red sun rises.
血红的太阳升起来了
Blood has been spilled this night.
昨晚一定是杀疆之夜
Riders of Rohan...
勇敢的罗罕国骑士
.. what news from the Mark?
罗罕国有什么消息吗
What business does an Elf, a Man and a Dwarf have in the Riddermark?
精灵 人类 矮人 来到罗罕之地有什么事
Speak quickly!
快点说
Give me your name, horse-master, and I shall give you mine.
你通报你的姓名 骑士 然后我会告诉你
! would cut off your head, Dwarf...
你要是再高一点 小矮人
.. if it stood but a little higher from the ground.
我会把你的头砍下来
You would die before your stroke fell.
那我就先射死你
lam Aragorn, son of Arathorn.
我是亚拉松之子阿拉贡
This is Gimli, son of Gloin, and Legolas of the Woodland Realm.
葛罗音的儿子金需 精灵王国的莱戈拉斯
We are friends of Rohan and of Théoden, your king.
我们是罗罕国和塞奥顿的朋友
Théoden no longer recognizes friend from foe.
塞奥顿国王现在已经是敌友不分
Not even his own kin.
他甚至六亲不认
Saruman has poisoned the mind of the king...
萨鲁曼毒害了国王的心
...and claimed lordship over these lands.
摧取了王国的土地
My company are those loyal to Rohan.
我的人都是王国的忠臣
And for that, we are banished.
我们因此遭到放逐
The White Wizard is cunning.
折袍巫师阴险狐诠
He walks here and there, they say...
有人匈他装扮成老者的模样
...as an old man hooded and cloaked.
出没于各地
And everywhere, his spies slip past our nets.
他的那些密探也无处不在
We are no spies.
我们不是密探
We track a party of Uruk-hai westward across the plain.
我们跟踪一些强兽人向西越过平原
They have taken two of our friends captive.
我们有两个朋友被抓走了
The Uruks are destroyed. We slaughtered them during the night.
那些强兽人昨天晚上 已经被我们消灭了
But there were two Hobbits. Did you see two Hobbits with them?
里面有两个需比特人 你看见他们了吗
They would be small. Only children to your eyes.
他们个子很矮小看起来就像孩子
We left none alive.
我们没留活口
We piled the carcasses and burned them.
尸体全都烧了
Dead?
死了?
lam sorry.
对不起
Hasufel! Arod!
哈苏风 阿罗德
May these horses bear you to better fortune than their former masters.
给 愿它们战死的主人保佑你们
Farewell.
再见
Look for your friends.
去找你们的朋友吧
But do not trust to hope.
别抱太大和希望
It has forsaken these lands.
罗罕国已经没有希望了
We ride north!
向北进发
It's one of their wee belts.
这是他们的腰带
We failed them.
看来我们来晚了
A Hobbit lay here.
你们看这儿 才比特人在这儿山过
And the other.
另一个在这儿
They crawled.
他们在下行
Their hands were bound.
双手被拉住
Their bonds were cut.
他们割断了绳索
They ran over here.
然后开始逃
They were followed.
有人在追他们
The belt!
腰带
Run!
快跑
Tracks lead away from the battle...
足迹离开战场
...into Fangorn Forest.
进入法贡森林
Fangorn?
法贡?
What madness drove them in there?
他们吃了和豹子胆?
Did we lose him? I think we lost him.
甩掉他了吗? 好像是甩掉了
I'm going to rip out your filthy little innards!
我要把你们大印八块
Trees. Climb a tree.
树 快上树
He's gone.
他走了
Merry!
梅里
Let's put a maggot hole in your belly!
我要在你的肚子上开天窗
Run, Merry!
梅里 快跑
Little Orcs.
小半兽人
It's talking, Merry. The tree is talking.
他在说话 梅里 树在说话
Tree?
树?
lam no tree!
我不是树
lam an Ent.
我是树形人
A tree-herder.
是森林守护者
A shepherd of the forest.
负责放牧森林
Don't talk to it, Merry.
别和他说话 梅里
Treebeard, some call me.
有人叫我树胡
And whose side are you on?
你帮助哪一边?
Side?
哪一边?
lam on nobody's side...
我谁也不帮
... because nobody's on my side, little Orc.
因为没人帮有我 小半兽人
Nobody cares for the woods anymore.
没有人在平树林
We're not Orcs! We're Hobbits!
我们不是半兽人 我们是蚌比特人
Hobbits?
霍比特人?
Never heard of a Hobbit before.
从没听说过有什么需比特人
Sounds like Orc mischief to me!
小半兽人 想糊弄我吧
They come with fire.
他们带火
Gnawing, biting, breaking, hacking, burning!
又砍又锯 还用火烧
-Destroyers and usurpers! Curse them! -No!
一毁灭者 强盗 该死的家人 -不
You don't understand. We're Hobbits!
你不明白 我们真是小个子埠比特人
Halflings!
昨比特人
Shire-folk!
夏尔人
Maybe you are...
也许是
...and maybe you aren't.
也许不是
The White Wizard?
白袍巫师?
Saruman.
萨重曼
See? See?
看到吗 看到吗
We've led you out.
我们带你们出来了
Hurry, Hobbitses. Hurry!
快点 起比特人
Very lucky we find you.
碰上你们很幸运
Nice Hobbit.
好起比特人
It's a bog. He's led us into a swamp.
沼泽 他把我们带进了沼泽
A swamp, yes, yes.
沼泽 是的
I found it. I did.
是我发现的
The way through the marshes.
沼泽中的小路
Orcs don't use it. Orcs don't know it.
半兽人是不会走这条路的
They go around for miles and miles.
他们不知道 他们要绕很远的路
Come quickly.
得快点
Soft and quick as shadows we must be.
我们要像幽灵一样球过去
There are dead things!
水里有死人
Dead faces in the water.
我看到了他们的面孔
All dead. All rotten.
都死了 腐烂了
Elves and Men and Orcses.
精灵 人类 还有半兽人
A great battle long ago.
多年前的一场大战
Dead Marshes.
死亡沼泽
Yes. Yes, that is their name.
是啊 那就是它的名字
Don't follow the lights.
要避开火光
Careful now! Or Hobbits go down to join the dead ones...
当心点 要不然 你们才比特人也会死去
...and light little candles of their own.
变成一团火焰
Frodo!
佛罗多
-Gollum? -Don't follow the lights.
=- 咕噜? -避开火光 要记住
-Gollum! -Mr. Frodo!
=咕噜 一佛罗多
Are you all right?
你没事吧
So bright.
闪闪发亮
So beautiful.
美丽无比
Our precious.
我们的宝贝
What did you say?
你在说什么
Master should be resting.
我说主人该休息了
Master needs to keep up his strength.
我说主人应该保持体力
-Who are you? -Mustn't ask us. Not its business.
一你是谁? =不关你事 你不要问
Gollum. Gollum.
咕噜 咕噜
Gandalf told me you were one of the river-folk.
甘道夫说你原先住在河边
Cold be heart and hand and bone Cold be travelers far from home
我是一个冷血动物 我是一个孤魂野彼
He said your life was a sad story.
他说你的经历非常坎坷
They do not see what lies ahead When sun has failed and moon is dead
星辰已落日夜无光 我看不到一丝一毫的希望
You were not so very different from a Hobbit once.
你曾经是和我们一样的蝴比特人
Were you?
对吗
Sméagol.
斯米格
What did you call me?
你叫我什么
That was your name once, wasn't it?
那曾是你的名字 对吗
A long time ago.
很久以前
My name.
我的名字
Sméagol.
斯米格
Black Riders!
黑骑士
Hide! Hide!
躲起来 躲起来
Come on, Frodo. Come on!
快点 佛罗多
Quick! They will see us! They will see us!
快 他们会发现我们
- thought they were dead. -Dead?
一我以为他们已经死了 一死了?
No, you cannot kill them. No.
不 他们不会被杀死
Wraiths on wings!
会飞的戒灵
They are calling for it.
他们在找魔戒
They are calling for the precious.
在找那件宝贝
Mr. Frodo! It's all right.
佛罗多 不会有事的
I'm here.
有我在
Hurry, Hobbits.
快点 起比特人
The Black Gate is very close.
魔多之门就要到了
These are strange tracks.
足迹很奇怪
The air is so close in here.
空气也非常混浊
This forest is old.
这片森林很古老
Very old.
非常古老
..and anger.
和愤友
The trees are speaking to each other.
这些树在相互交谈
Lower your ax.
放下萄子
The White Wizard approaches.
折袍巫师来了 就在附近
Do not let him speak. He will put a spell on us.
他会对我们施魔法 别让他说话
We must be quick.
动作一定要快
You are tracking the footsteps of two young Hobbits.
你们在寻找两个蝴比特人
Where are they?
他们在哪儿
They passed this way the day before yesterday.
他们前天从这个地方经过
They met someone they did not expect.
他们遇到了料想之外的好心人
Does that comfort you?
你们放心了吧
Who are you?
你是谁?
Show yourself!
把脸露出来
You fell.
你掉下去了
Through fire...
穿过
...and water.
烈焰激流
From the lowest dungeon to the highest peak...
从无底深渊到万丈高峰
...¢ fought with the Balrog of Morgoth.
我与炎魔怪决一死战
Until at last { threw down my enemy...
最后我终于将他打败
..and smote his ruin upon the mountainside.
把他的尸体摔下山谷
Darkness took me...
黑暗将我笼罩
...and { strayed out of thought and time.
我失去了意念和时间
..and every day was as long as a life age of the Earth.
光阴难握 真是度日如年
But it was not the end.
但一切并没有结束
! felt life in me again.
我的生命再次复苏
I've been sent back...
我又一次受到召唤
...Until my task is done.
直至完成使命
Gandalf.
甘道夫
Gandalf?
甘道夫?
Yes.
是的
That was what they used to call me.
那是我以前的名字
Gandalf the Grey.
灰移甘道夫
That was my name.
那是我的名字
Gandalf.
甘道夫
lam Gandalf the White.
现在我是白袍甘道夫
And I come back to you now...
在命运转折之际
...at the turn of the tide.
我又回来了
One stage of your journey is over. Another begins.
你们新的行程已经开始
War has come to Rohan. We must ride to Edoras with all speed.
罗罕国狼烟四起 我们要赶往伊多拉斯 胡夜兼程
That is one of the Mearas...
我没有看错吧
...unless my eyes are cheated by some spell.
那是一匹米亚拉斯
Shadowfax.
这是影疾
He is the lord of all horses...
它是马中之王
..and has been my friend through many dangers.
在我危难之际便会出现
My home lies deep in the forest...
我的家在森林深处
... near the roots of the mountain.
位于山根之下
I told Gandalf ! would keep you safe.
我答应甘道夫保证你们的安全
And safe is where I'll keep you.
那将是我的使命
The trees have grown wild and dangerous.
纵冠树已经变得疯狂而危险
Anger festers in their hearts.
它们心中积怨已久
They will harm you if they can.
只要有可能就会伤害你们
There are too few of us now.
我们树人已所剩无几
Too few of us Ents left to manage them.
已经没有足够的力量管束它们
The Black Gate of Mordor.
看哪 主人 魔多之门
Oh, save us.
侥恕我们
My old Gaffer would have a thing or two to say if he could see us now.
如果我老爸在这儿他一定有话要说
Master says to show him the way into Mordor.
主人说让我带他来魔多
So good Sméagol does, master says so.
主人说斯米格干得漂亮
did.
是的
That's it, then.
这下完了
We can't get past that.
我们进不去了
Look!
看哪
The gate.
那扇门
It's opening!
它打开了
l can see a way down.
我能看到下山的路
Sam, no!
山姆 不
Master!
我的主人
-! do not ask you to come with me, Sam. -l Know, Mr. Frodo.
一我没要求你跟我进去 山姆 一我知道 佛罗多老爷
I doubt even these Elvish cloaks will hide us in there.
这件精灵斗篷未必能掩人耳上日
-Now! -No!
一来吧 -不
No! No, master!
不 主人
They catch you! They catch you!
他们会抓住你的
Don't take it to him.
不 二万不要自自送给他
He wants the precious.
他想要那件宝贝
Always he is looking for it.
他一直在找它
And the precious is wanting to go back to him.
那件宝贝也很想回到他身边
But we mustn't let him have it.
可我们绝不能让他得退
No! There's another way.
不 还有一条路
More secret. A dark way.
更加隐藏 一个秘密通道
-Why haven't you spoken of this before? -Because master did not ask.
-那你为什么不早告诉我们 一因为主人从来没有问过我
Are you saying there's another way into Mordor?
还有一条路能进入魔多?
Yes. There's a path...
是的 一条小路
...and some stairs.
然后是人台阶
And then...
再往后
...a tunnel.
是隧道
He's led us this far, Sam.
我们能到这儿全靠他指引
Mr. Frodo, no.
佛罗多老他 不行
He's been true to his word.
可他一直信守诺言
No.
不行
Lead the way, Sméagol.
带路吧 斯米格
Good Sméagol always helps.
斯米格愿意效劳
Edoras and the Golden Hall of Meduseld.
伊多拉斯和有罗罕国王的金殿到了
There dwells Théoden, King of Rohan...
那里住着罗罕国王塞奥顿
... whose mind is overthrown.
他的精神已被完全控制
Saruman's hold over King Théoden is now very strong.
萨鲁曼已经把他牢牢掌握在手中
My lord, your son...
我的国王 你的儿子
..he is dead.
已经死了
My lord?
我的国王
Uncle?
男 男
Will you not go to him?
你不去看他吗
Will you do nothing?
你难道无动于袁
Be careful what you say.
你们说话一定谨慎
Do not look for welcome here.
不要奢望受到款待
Oh, he must have died sometime in the night.
他一定是在夜里死去的
What a tragedy for the king...
多么悲惨的一幕
...to lose his only son and heir.
国王失去了他的独子和继承人
understand. His passing is hard to accept.
我知道他的死让人无法接受
Especially now that your brother has deserted you.
尤其是在你哥哥离你而去之际
Leave me alone, snake!
让我安静些 毒蛇
Oh, but you are alone.
可是你如此孤独
Who knows what you've spoken to the darkness...
谁知道你会在黑暗中说些什么
..in the bitter watches of the night...
夯对玫寞的长夜
...when all your life seems to shrink.
任凭你的生命渐渐枯萎
The walls of your bower closing in about you.
你的闺房之门已紧锁
A hutch to trammel some wild thing in.
它使你温望自由的心灵感到窒息
So fair.
那么漂亮
So cold.
那么冰冷
Like a morning of pale spring...
就像寒气去人的早春的黎明
...Still clinging to winter's chill.
没有摆脱严冬的束缚
Your words are poison.
你的话就像毒药
You'll find more cheer in a graveyard.
这里比坟墓还要阴森
I cannot allow you before Théoden King so armed, Gandalf Greyhame.
你们不可以扒带武器讽见 塞奥顿国王 甘道夫巫师
By order of Grima Wormtongue.
这是三寸舌葛力马的命令
Your staff.
还有你的
You would not part an old man from his walking stick.
你不会让一个老人家 离开自己的依靠吧
My lord, Gandalf the Grey is coming.
我的国王 灰物甘道夫巫师来了
He's a herald of woe.
灾难降临了
The courtesy of your hall is somewhat lessened of late...
你的金殿之上未免少了 一些应有的礼仪
.. Théoden King.
塞奥顿国王
He's not welcome.
他不受欢迎
Why should I welcome you...
我为什么要欢迎你
...Gandalf Stormcrow?
甘道夫车事生韭
A just question, my liege.
国王 你说得真是太好了
Late is the hour...
太晚了
..in which this conjurer chooses to appear.
你这姗姗来迟的巫师
Lathspell 1 name him.
你只会患惑人心
Ill news is an ill guest.
妩言惑众者是不受欢迎的
Be silent. Keep your forked tongue behind your teeth.
住口 管住你这三寸不烂之舌
l have not passed through fire and death...
我历尽干辛万苦赶来
...to bandy crooked words with a witless worm.
不是为了跟你这素货过招
His staff.
他的手杖
I told you to take the wizard's staff.
我让你们拿去巫师的手杖
Théoden...
塞奥顿
...$on of Thengel...
塞格尔国王之子
...too long have you sat in the Shadows.
你被妖术迷惑得太久了
would stay still if 1 were you.
我要是你 就老实待着
Hearken to me!
听我说
l release you...
让我来解除
...from the spell.
你的咒语
You have no power here...
你没有足够的法力
... Gandalf the Grey.
灰移甘道夫
I will draw you, Saruman, as poison is drawn from a wound.
我要驱除你 萨重曼 就像驱除伤口的毒液
Wait.
等等
If l go, Théoden dies.
如果我离开 塞奥顿必有死
You did not kill me...
你杀不死我
Rohan is mine.
甘道夫 罗罕国是我的
Be gone.
不再是了
I know your face.
我认得你的脸
Gandalf?
甘道夫
Breathe the free air again, my friend.
自由地呼吸吧 我的朋友
Dark have been my dreams of late.
我一直沉睡在焉梦中
Your fingers would remember their old strength better...
你的手如果握住宝剑
...if they grasped your sword.
一定会像从前一样有力
I've only...
国王
...ever served you, my lord.
我一直对你忠心耿取
Your leechcraft would have had me crawling on all fours like a beast!
你的妖术险些让我变成衣冠禽兽
Send me not from your sight.
请你贷恕我吧 我的国王
No, my lord! No, my lord.
不 国王 你等一等
Let him go.
让他去吧
Enough blood has been spilt on his account.
由他引起的血腥已经太多了
Get out of my way!
快内开
Hail, Théoden King!
万岁 塞奥顿国王
Where is Théodred?
塞奥德雷德在哪儿
Where is my son?
我儿子在哪儿
Ever has it grown on the tombs of my forebearers.
它从来只在我祖先的墓地上开放
Now it shall cover the grave of my son.
如今也会覆盖我儿子坟芝
Alas that these evil days should be mine.
天哪 我的生活竟然 有过如此的黑暗
The young perish and the old linger.
年少的先走 年老的留下
That ! should live...
我儿子
...to see the last days of my house.
再也不能继承我的王位
Théodred's death was not of your making.
你儿子塞奥德雷德的死 不是你的错
No parent should have to bury their child.
自发人不该送黑发人
He was strong in life.
他生前无比坚强
His spirit will find its way to the halls of your fathers.
他的灵魂一定会和你的祖先团聚
They had no warning.
他们不宣而战
They were unarmed.
我们手无寸铁
Now the Wild Men are moving through the Westfold, burning as they go.
那些野人正在西部 横冲直撞一路烧杀
Rick, cot and tree.
无恶不作
Where is Mama?
妈妈在哪儿
This is but a taste of the terror that Saruman will unleash.
这不过是萨备曼血腥屠杀的开始
All the more potent for he is driven now by fear of Sauron.
他的凶残完全是出于对索伦的恐惧
Ride out and meet him head on.
你该挺身而出
Draw him away from your women and children.
那样才能解救妇女和儿童
You must fight.
必须战斗
You have 2000 good men riding north as we speak.
你有两千精兵日前正在北方作战
. Eomer is loyal to you.
伊欧墨是你的忠臣
His men will return and fight for their king.
他的人会回来为国王而战的
They will be 300 leagues from here by now.
他们离这儿至少1千5百公里
. Eomer cannot help us.
伊欧墨也帮不了我们
know what it is you want of me...
我明折你的意思
...but I will not bring further death to my people.
可我不想让更多人民死于韭难
I will not risk open war.
我不能冒险开战
Open war is upon you, whether you would risk it or not.
不管你是否愿意 战争已经开始了
When last I looked...
不过说到底
.. Théoden, not Aragorn, was king of Rohan.
罗罕国王是塞奥顿不是阿拉贡
Then what is the king's decision?
国王现在有什么决定
By order of the King...
国王有令
...the city must empty.
全体离城
We make for the refuge of Helm's Deep.
我们将去朱尔穆斯峡谷避难
Do not burden yourself with treasures. Take only what provisions you need.
请大家轻装简从 随身只携带生活用品
Helm's Deep.
炙尔穆斯峡谷
They flee to the mountains when they should stand and fight.
当需要战斗时他们却要逃进深山
Who will defend them if not their king?
除了国王谁还能保护他们
He's only doing what he thinks is best for his people.
他一定认为这是 保护人民的最佳方式
Helm's Deep has saved them in the past.
那峡谷曾经挽救过他们
There is no way out of that ravine. Théoden is walking into a trap.
那条峡谷没有出口 去那里是死路一条
He thinks he's leading them to safety.
他以为那儿安全
What they will get is a massacre.
但他们只能遭到血腥屠杀
Théoden has a strong will, but I fear for him.
塞奥顿意志坚定 但我却担心
fear for the survival of Rohan.
我担心罗罕国的安危存亡
He will need you before the end, Aragorn.
最后关头他需要 你们的帮助 阿拉贡
The people of Rohan will need you.
罗军人民需要你们
The defenses have to hold.
他们必须有人捍卫
They will hold.
在所不辞
The Grey Pilgrim.
灰移巫师
That's what they used to call me.
这是我过去的名字
Three hundred lives of Men I've walked this earth, and now ! have no time.
我已在这儿生活了3百代 如今我的时间不多了
With luck, my search will not be in vain.
但愿此行能够找到救兵
Look to my coming at first light on the fifth day.
当第5天的第一缕曙光出现 我就会回来
At dawn, look to the east.
注意黎明时的东方
Go.
去吧
You have some skill with a blade.
你的剑法不错
Women of this country learned long ago:
罗罕女人自幼习武
Those without swords can still die upon them.
没有剑的人迟早会死于剑下
fear neither death nor pain.
我不怕苦也不怕死
What do you fear, my lady?
那么你怕的是什么
A cage.
牢筹
To stay behind bars until use and old age accept them.
我怕上时间和年龄会 让我适应牢笼生活
And all chance of valor has gone beyond recall or desire.
我怕我的勇气有一天会消失至尽
You're a daughter of kings...
你是王国的公主
1 do not think that would be your fate.
你担心的事永远不会发生
Théoden will not stay at Edoras.
塞奥顿不会留在伊多拉斯
It's vulnerable. He knows this.
那里不堪一击
They will flee to Helm's Deep...
他们会逃亡赫尔穆斯峡谷
.. the great fortress of Rohan.
那里是罗罕人的天然要塞
it is a dangerous road to take through the mountains.
进山的路十分险恶
They will have women and children with them.
因为他们带着老幼妇
Send out your Warg-riders.
让野狼骑士马上出发
Hey, stinker, don't go getting too far ahead.
栖货 别跑得太运
-Why do you do that? -What?
一你怎么这样 一怎样了
Call him names. Run him down all the time.
随便轨人 老是找他的别扭
Because.
因为
Because that's what he is, Mr. Frodo.
因为他就是个民贷
There's naught left in him but lies and deceit.
除了撒谎和欺骗他什么都不会
It's the Ring he wants. It's all he cares about.
他要的是魔戒 他只关心魔戒
You have no idea what it did to him...
你不知道他有多伤心
l want to help him, Sam.
我想帮助他 山姆
Why?
为什么
Because I have to believe he can come back.
我坚信他能够醒悟
You can't save him, Mr. Frodo.
你帮不了他 佛罗多老他
What do you know about it? Nothing!
你懂什么 你不慌
I do.
我知道
You can't take your eyes off it.
你的日光一刻也离不开它
You're not eating. You barely sleep.
看看你 不吃也不睡
It's taken hold of you, Mr. Frodo.
魔戒已经控制了你
-You have to fight it. - Know what ! have to do, Sam.
一你必须抗争 一我知道应该怎么做
The Ring was entrusted to me. It's my task.
保管魔戒是我的职责 是我的任务
Mine! My own!
是我的 我自己的
Don't you know who you sound like?
你知道自己像谁的腔调吗
We wants it.
我们需要它
Must have the precious.
不能没有那个宝贝
They stole it from us.
那是他们偷我们的
Sneaky little Hobbitses.
下贱的堆比特人
Wicked. Tricksy. False.
那恶狂诠 虚伪
No. Not master.
不 主人他不是
Yes, precious. False.
他是 亲爱的 他虚伪
They will cheat you, hurt you, lie!
他们会鞭负你 伤害你 骗你
Master's my friend.
主人是我朋友
You don't have any friends. Nobody likes you.
你没有朋友 没人会喜欢你
Not listening. I'm not listening.
我不听 我不听
You're a liar and a thief.
你是允子 是个贼
No.
不
Murderer.
谋杀犯
Go away.
你走开
Go away?
走开?
l hate you.
我恨你
I saved us.
我得救咱们
It was me. We survived because of me.
就是我 没有我就没有你
Not anymore.
不 别说了
What did you say?
你说什么
Master looks after us now.
我现在有主人照顾
We don't need you.
我们不再需要你
What?
什么
Leave now...
离开我
...and never come back.
永远别再回来
No.
不
Leave now and never come back.
离开我 永远别再回来
Leave now and never come back!
离开我 永远别再回来了
We told him to go away.
他真的走了
And away he goes, precious.
他真的离开我了 亲爱的
Gone! Gone! Gone!
他走了 他走了
Sméagol is free!
斯米格自由了
Look.
你看哪
Look. See what Sméagol finds?
看哪 斯米格找到了什么
They are young.
是小兔子
They are tender. They are nice.
鲜嫩 美味
Yes, they are. Eat them. Eat them!
没错 吃吧
...behaving like that.
瞧你这份德性
There's only one way to eat a brace of coneys.
告诉你吃免肉只有一种方法
What's it doing?
你干什么
Stupid, fat Hobbit.
答归 胖猪
It ruins it.
你已经毁了美味了
What's to ruin? There's hardly any meat on them.
毁什么 上面根本没有肉
What we need is a few good taters.
我想我们需要一些土豆
What's taters, precious?
什么是土豆? 是宝贝吗
What's taters? Eh?
什么是土豆
Po-ta-toes.
马铃薯
Boil them, mash them, stick them in a stew.
煮熟了然后的成泥
Lovely, big, golden chips with a nice piece of fried fish.
放进炖锅里真是太美了 金黄色的大苗条配上炸鱼
Even you couldn't say no to that.
就连你也不能抗拒
Oh, yes, we could.
不 我能
Spoil a nice fish.
那你就把鱼毁了
Give it to us raw...
我要吃生的
..and wriggling.
我要吃活的
You keep nasty chips.
你自己去吃烂莉条好了
You're hopeless.
真是无可救药
Mr. Frodo?
佛罗多老他
-Who are they? -Wicked Men.
一他们是什么人? -是坏人
Servants of Sauron.
是索伦的奴仆
They are called to Mordor.
他们泰命去魔多
The Dark One is gathering all armies to him.
黑暗魔君正在调动所有军队
It won't be long now. He will soon be ready.
不用太久他就准备好了
-Ready to do what? -To make his war.
一准备什么? 一准备战争
The last war that will cover all the world in Shadow.
就是把全世界拖入黑暗的最后之战
We've got to get moving. Come on, Sam.
我们必须马上动身 走吧 山姆
Mr. Frodo.
佛罗多老他
Look.
你瞧
It's an oliphaunt.
那是独玛
No one at home will believe this.
家乡人肯定不会相信
Sméagol?
斯米格
We've lingered here too long.
我们耿搁太久了
Come on, Sam.
快走 山姆
It's true, you don't see many Dwarf women.
真的 你没见过什么女矮人
...that they're often mistaken for Dwarf men.
你甚至常常会男女不分
It's the beards.
她们都长胡子
This, in turn, has given rise to the belief...
所以人们相信
...that there are no Dwarf women...
根本没有女性矮人
...and that Dwarves just spring out of holes in the ground...
所有的矮人都是从地洞里钻出来的
...which is, of course, ridiculous.
当然是无稽之谈
It's all right. Nobody panic.
没关系 大家别慌
That was deliberate. It was deliberate.
我是故意摔的
The light of the Evenstar does not wax and wane.
埃文斯塔的灯光永远不会消失
It is mine to give to whom { will.
我把它送给心爱的人
Like my heart.
就像我的心
Go to sleep.
去睡吧
lam asleep.
好的 我已经睡了
This is a dream.
这是一个梦
Then it is a good dream.
一定是个好梦
Sleep.
睡吧
Arwen...
亚玫
Where is she?
她在哪儿
The woman who gave you that jewel.
那个送你宝石的女人
Our time here is ending.
我们该走了
Arwen's time is ending.
亚孜也一样
Let her go.
让她走吧
Let her take the ship into the west.
让她乘船去西部吧
Let her bear away her love for you to the Undying Lands.
让她带着你的爱去那个永恒的地方
There it will be ever green.
你的爱在那里会永远伴随着她
But never more than memory.
但那只会是个回忆
I will not leave my daughter here to die.
我不能把女儿留在这里等死
-She stays because she still has hope. -She stays for you.
一她留下是因为抱有和希望 一她留下来是因为你
She belongs with her people.
她属于她的人民
Why are you saying this?
你为什么这样说
lam mortal. You are Elf-kind.
我是凡人 你是精灵
It was a dream, Arwen.
我们两个在做梦 亚玉
Nothing more.
仅此而已
This belongs to you.
这是你的 亚玫
It was a gift.
是我的礼物
Keep it.
拿着吧
My lord?
大王
She is sailing to the Undying Lands with all that is left of her kin.
她和她的人民已经 乘船去了永恒之地
What is it?
怎么回事?
-Hama? -l'm not sure.
- 哈玛? -不清楚
Wargs!
又狼骑士
A scout!
是侦察兵
-What is it? What do you see? -Warg! We're under attack!
一怎么回事 你看到什么 一野狼骑士 我们受到攻击
Get them out of here!
野狼骑士进攻了
All riders to the head of the column.
所有骑兵到前面集合
Come on. Get me up here. I'm a rider.
快点让我上去 我是骑士
Come on!
快点
You must lead the people to Helm's Deep, and make haste.
你一定要把大家这到赫尔穆斯山谷
-l can fight. -No!
一我能打佼 -不
You must do this, for me.
这是命令 为了我
Follow me!
跟我来
-Forward. ! mean, charge forward. -Make for the lower ground!
一冲啊 快点冲啊 一大家快下山
-That's it! Go on! -Stay together!
一对了 前进 =-不要掉队
Bring your pretty face to my ax.
让你尝党大爷的斧头
That one counts as mine!
那是我的功劳
Stinking creature.
臭杂种
Tell me what happened and I will ease your passing.
快说到底出了什么事 否则立刻砍了你
He's...
他
... dead.
死了
He took a little tumble off the cliff.
掉下嫩崖扩死了
You lie.
你撒谎
Get the wounded on horses.
把伤者拖上马硼
The wolves of Isengard will return.
艾圣格的野狼还会再来
Leave the dead.
留下死者
Come.
走吧
-At last! -Helm's Deep.
-终于到了 - 赫尔穆斯峡谷
There it is, Helm's Deep.
到了 赫尔穆斯峡谷
We're safe!
我们安全了
We're safe, my lady.
我们安全了 我们安全了 公主
Thank you.
谢谢你
-Mama! . -Eothain!
一妈妈 一伊欧参
Freda!
斐代
Make way for Théoden. Make way for the king.
给国王让路
So few. So few of you have returned.
就你们几个 就回来你们几个
Our people are safe.
我的人民安全了
We have paid for it with many lives.
那是用生命换来的
My lady.
公主
Lord Aragorn...
阿拉贡大王呢
... where is he?
他在哪儿
He fell.
他去了
Bar the gate. And set a watch on the surround.
天闭城门 加强警戒
What of those who cannot fight, my lord? The women and children?
韭战斗人员怎么办 女人和孩子
Get them into the caves.
让他们进入地酒
Helm's Deep has one weakness.
炙尔穆斯峡谷无懈可击
its outer wall is solid rock...
围墙都是坚固的岩石
...but for a smail culvert at its base...
只有墙下的酒酒是它的薄弱之处
... Which is little more than a drain.
类似下水管道
How? How can fire undo stone?
怎么 火怎么能烧毁石头
What kind of device could bring down the wall?
什么装置可以毁掉城墙?
If the wall is breached, Helm's Deep will fall.
如果把城墙打开缺口 炙尔穆斯峡谷就会骨溃
Even if it is breached, it would take a number beyond reckoning...
就算把城墙打开 没有成千上万的军队
... thousands, to storm the Keep.
也休想攻下要塞
But, my lord, there is no such force.
可是大王 我们没有那么多军队
A new power is rising.
一股新势力正在崛起
Its victory is at hand.
胜利已经在掌握之中
This night...
就在今晚
...the land will be stained with the blood of Rohan!
那里就要酒满罗罕人的鲜血
March to Helm's Deep!
向赫尔穆斯峡谷进军
Leave none alive!
杀他个鸡大不留
To war!
开战
There will be no dawn for Men.
人类的末日到了
Look. There's smoke to the south.
瞧啊 南方在冒烟
There is always smoke rising...
这些日子艾驻格
...from Isengard these days.
一直浓烟滚滚
Isengard?
艾笠格?
There was a time...
曾几何时
... when Saruman would walk in my woods.
萨鲁曼经常光顾我们的森林
But now he has a mind of metal...
但是现在他只想着金属
..and wheels.
和战车
He no longer cares for growing things.
对种杆已经不感兴趣了
What is it?
那是什么
It's Saruman's army.
是萨曾曼的大军
The war has started.
战争开始了
May the grace of the Valar protect you.
愿神灵保佑你
Arwen.
亚玫
l have made my choice.
我已做出决定
He is not coming back.
他不会回来了
Why do you linger here when there is no hope?
你何若留在这没有和希望之地
There is still hope.
希望永远存在
If Aragorn survives this war, you will still be parted.
即使阿拉贡打赢 你们还是会分开
If Sauron is defeated and Aragorn made king...
就算索伦被打败 阿拉贡恢复王位
..and all that you hope for comes true...
你们宿愿成真
.. you will still have to taste the bitterness of mortality.
他仍然摆脱不了人尘世苦海
Whether by the sword or the slow decay of time...
血光之灾 无情岁月
.. Aragorn will die.
他终究难免一死
And there will be no comfort for you...
那时你将无以奈籍
...0 comfort fo ease the pain of his passing.
心中的伤痛再也无法抚平
He will come to death...
他注定会死去
...an image of the splendor of the kings of Men...
在改朝换代之际带着
..in glory undimmed before the breaking of the world.
人类之王的崇高尊严和不灭光环
But you, my daughter...
而你 我的女儿
... you will linger on in darkness and in doubt...
你将永远在黑暗中衍笋徘徊
...a8 nightfall in winter that comes without a star.
就如同不见一丝星光的冬日夜晚
Here you will dwell...
你将带着无以挂解的贱帐
... bound to your grief under the fading trees...
在枯树下位立
...until all the world is changed...
直到翻天覆地之日
Arwen.
亚玫
There is nothing for you here...
你在这儿什么也得不到
..only death.
除了死亡
The power of the enemy is growing.
敌人的能量正在加强
Sauron will use his puppet, Saruman...
索伦将利用他的盆偶萨曾曼
...fo destroy the people of Rohan.
消灭罗罕人民
lsengard has been unleashed.
艾闻格魔鬼已经出筹
The Eye of Sauron now turns to Gondor...
索伦的日光转向刚铎
...the last free kingdom of Men.
这人类最后的自由王国
He senses the Ring is close.
他感觉到魔戒已经临近
The strength of the Ring-bearer is failing.
魔戒持有者的力量正在锐减
In his heart, Frodo begins fo understand...
佛罗多心里明握
...the quest will claim his life.
他此行凶多吉少
You know this.
你很清楚这一天
You have foreseen it.
你预见到了
It is the risk we ail took.
这是我们大家的危险
in the gathering dark, the will of the Ring grows strong.
随着黑暗势力的集结 魔戒的意志力越来越强
it works hard now fo find its way back into the hands of Men.
它正在极力想要回到人类手中
Men, who are so easily seduced by its power.
因为人类最容易受它的魔力诱惑
The young captain of Gondor has but to extend his hand...
刚铎的年轻将军只需举手之劳
...fake the Ring for his own, and the world will fall.
便能得到它 世界也将随之毁灭
It is close now.
已经不远了
So close to achieving its goal.
魔戒就要达到它的日的
For Sauron will have dominion over ail life on this Earth...
索伦将会统治全世界的生灵
...even unto fo the ending of the world.
包括毁灭世界的权力
The time of the Elves...
精灵的时代
. . AS Over.
结束了
Do we leave Middle-earth to its fate?
我们能对中土的命运置若国闻?
Do we let them stand alone?
能让他们孤军奋战吗
What news?
情况如何?
Our scouts report Saruman has attacked Rohan.
侦察部队报告 萨重曼已经开始进攻罗罕国
Théoden's people have fled to Helm's Deep.
塞奥顿的人逃进了赫尔穆斯峡谷
But we must look to our own borders. Faramir, Orcs are on the move.
但我们必须注意自己的边界 法拉米尔 萨重曼正在硒琳欲动
Sauron is marshaling an army.
索伦正在组织军队
-How many? -Some thousands. More come every day.
一多少人? 一成和干上万 每天还在增加
-Who's covering the river to the north? -We pulled 500 men at Osgiliath.
一谁负责把守北部边界? - 5百名吉奥斯吉力亚斯人
If their city is attacked, we won't hold it.
如果那座城市受到攻击 我们很难守住
Saruman attacks from Isengard.
萨鲁曼从艾储格方向进攻
Sauron from Mordor.
索伦则从魔多进攻
The fight will come to Men on both fronts.
我们人类将面临两条战线
Gondor is weak.
刚铎危在旦夕
Sauron will strike us soon.
索伦很快会进攻我们
And he will strike hard.
而且会极其疯狂
He knows now we do not have the strength to repel him.
他知道我们日前无力还手
My men tell me that you are Orc spies.
我的部下说你们是半兽人间谍
Spies? Now wait just a minute.
间谍? 你们把话说清楚
Well, if you're not spies, then who are you?
不是间谍那你们是什么人
We are Hobbits of the Shire.
我们是夏尔国的埠比特人
Frodo Baggins is my name, and this is Samwise Gamgee.
我叫佛罗多“' 巴金斯 他是山姆怀斯， 甘姆齐
Your bodyguard?
你的保镖?
His gardener.
他的园丁
And where is your skulking friend?
你们那些鬼鬼崇景的朋友了呢
That gangrel creature.
那些流溪汉
He had an ill-favored look.
长着丑陋的外残
There was no other.
没别人了
We set out from Rivendell with seven companions.
我们从瑞文戴尔出发时有7个人
One we lost in Moria...
一人死在了摩瑞亚
...two were my kin...
两个夫比特人
...a Dwarf there was also. And an Elf and two Men.
一个矮人 一个精灵 两个人类
Aragorn, son of Arathorn, and Boromir of Gondor.
他们是阿拉松之子阿拉贡 和刚铎人博罗米尔
You're a friend of Boromir?
你是博罗米尔的朋友?
Yes.
是的
For my part.
我想是的
It will grieve you then to learn that he is dead.
如果知道他死了你们一定很伤心
Dead?
死了?
How? When?
怎么死的 什么时候
As one of his companions, I'd hoped you would tell me.
你是他的朋友 你应该清楚
He was my brother.
他是我的哥哥
Captain Faramir!
法拉米尔队长
We found the third one.
我们又找到一个
You must come with me. Now.
你得马上跟我来
Down there.
看下面
To enter the Forbidden Pool bears the penalty of death.
跳入禁池的人必须被处死
They wait for my command.
他们在等我的命令
Shall 1 shoot?
可以发射
The rock and pool is nice and cool
当中有个小水塘
So juicy sweet
空气舒服又清凉
Our only wish To catch a fish
别的什么也不想
So juicy sweet
抓条鱼儿来尝党
Wait.
等等
This creature is bound to me.
他对我负有责任
And I to him.
我对他也是
He is our guide.
他是我的问导
Please...
求你
...let me go down to him.
让我下去见他吧
Sméagol.
斯米格
Master is here.
主人来了
Come, Sméagol.
过来 斯米格
Trust master. Come.
相信主人 过来
We must go now?
我们是该走了吗
Sméagol, you must trust master.
斯米格 你一定要相信主人
Follow me. Come on.
跟我来 过来
Come.
来吧
Come, Sméagol.
来吧 斯米格
Nice Sméagol. That's it.
好斯米格 这就对了
Come on.
快点
Don't hurt him!
不要伤害他
Sméagol, don't struggle. Sméagol, listen to me.
斯米格 不要挣扎 斯米格 听话
Master!
我的主人
No! No!
不不
Sméagol.
斯米格
Why does it cry, Sméagol?
你怎么虹了 斯米格
Cruel Men hurts us.
坏人伤害了我
Master tricksed us.
主人欺骗了我
Of course he did.
他当然会欺骗你
I told you he was tricksy.
我说过他很狂猫
I told you he was false.
我说过他是个骗子
Master is our friend.
主人是我朋友
Our friend.
我们的朋友
Master betrayed us.
主人背关了你
No. Not its business.
不 不关你事
Leave us alone!
让我安静会儿
Filthy little Hobbitses!
可亚的小埠比特人
They stole it from us!
他们偷了我们的宝贝
No. No.
不不
What did they steal?
他们偷了什么
My precious!
我的宝贝
We have to get out of here.
我们得离开这儿
You go. Go, now.
你走吧 马上就走
You can do it.
你能办到
Use the Ring, Mr. Frodo.
利用魔戒 佛罗多老爷
Just this once.
就这一次
Put it on.
快戴上它
Disappear.
消失掉
I can't.
我不能
You were right, Sam.
你说得对 山姆
You tried to tell me but...
你曾经劝过我 可是
I'm sorry.
对不起
The Ring's taking me, Sam.
魔戒控制了我 山姆
If l put it on...
如果我戴上它
...he'll find me.
就会被索伦发现
He'll see.
他会看到我
Mr. Frodo....
佛罗多老他
So this is the answer to all the riddles.
原来这就是谜底所在
Here in the Wild I have you...
在荒蛮之地我拥有了你们
...two Halflings...
两个半残废
...and a host of men at my call.
和无数人类
The Ring of Power within my grasp.
魔戒离我近在由尺
A chance for Faramir, captain of Gondor...
刚铎的大将法拉米尔终于能够
...to show his quality.
大显身手了
No!
不
Leave him alone.
你不许动他
Don't you understand?
你难道不明白吗
He's got to destroy it!
他必须把它销毁
That's where we're going, into Mordor.
所以我们要去魔多
To the Mountain of Fire!
去魔多火山
Osgiliath is under attack. They call for reinforcements.
奥斯吉力亚斯受到攻击 他们要求增援
Please. It's such a burden.
求你了 他已经不堪重负
Will you not help him?
你不想帮帮他吗
Captain?
队长
Prepare to leave.
准备撤离
The Ring will go to Gondor.
魔戒跟我去刚铎
Get out of the way! I'm going to kill him!
让开 我要杀了他
You are the luckiest, the canniest...
你是世界上最幸运 最机敏
...and the most reckless man I ever knew.
最大胆的家伙
Bless you, laddie.
上帝保佑你
Gimli, where is the king?
伙计 国王在哪儿
You look terrible.
气色不太好
A great host, you say?
他们人很多 是吗
-All Ilsengard is emptied. -How many?
一 艾壮格倾梨而出 - 有多少
Ten thousand strong at least.
至少有一万人
Ten thousand?
一万人?
It is an army bred for a single purpose:
那些军队他们只有一个日的
To destroy the world of Men.
就是毁灭我们人类
They will be here by nightfall.
傍晚他们会到这儿
l want every man and strong lad able to bear arms...
我命令所有能够拿起武器的人
...to be ready for battle by nightfall.
做好夜战准备
We will cover the causeway and the gate from above.
我们要从城墙上把守通道和大门
No army has ever breached the Deeping Wall...
还没有谁能够打破城墙
...or set foot inside the Hornburg!
进到要塞里边
This is no rabble of mindless Orcs.
这次可不是那些没心没肺的半兽人
These are Uruk-hai.
他们是强兽人
Their armour is thick and their shields broad.
有坚厚的盔甲和宽大的盾牌
l have fought many wars, Master Dwarf.
我是身经百战之人 矮人先生
I know how to defend my own keep.
我知道怎样保卫自己的领地
They will break upon this fortress like water on rock.
我会让他们没有用武之地
Saruman's hordes will pillage and burn. We've seen it before.
萨重曼的军队只会烧杀抢掠 我们早已领教
Crops can be resown...
但是庄稼可以再种
...homes rebuilt.
家园可以再建
Within these walls...
我们将在城墙之内
...we will outlast them.
坚守到他们退兵
They do not come to destroy Rohan's crops or villages.
他们才不是为了罗罕的城堡和庄稼
They come to destroy its people...
他们的日的是为了消灭罗罕人民
...down to the last child.
彻底灭绝
What would you have me do?
你想让我怎么样
Look at my men.
看看我的臣民
Their courage hangs by a thread.
他们的勇气并没有消失至尽
If this is to be our end, then ! would have them make such an end...
如果这是罗罕的末日 那我一定会让他们的死
...as to be worthy of remembrance.
永远载入史册
Send out riders, my lord.
派信使吧 国王
You must call for aid.
必须请求支援
And who will come?
有谁会来支援?
Elves?
精灵?
Dwarves?
矮人?
The old alliances are dead.
过去的联盟已经瓦解了
-Gondor will answer. -Gondor?!
=-刚铎会响应的 -刚铎
Where was Gondor when the Westfold fell?!
罗罕西部陷落时刚色在哪儿
Where was Gondor when our enemies closed in around us?!
敌人把我们团团包围时刚铎在哪儿
No, my Lord Aragorn...
不 阿拉贡
Get the women and children into the caves.
让妇女和儿童进入山酒
We need more time to lay provisions--
我们还需要点时间
There is no time. War is upon us.
没时间了 战争迫在眉睫
Secure the gate.
守住大门
We Ents have not troubled...
我们已经很久
...about the wars of Men and wizards...
没有参与人类
...for a very long time.
与焉师的战争了
But now, something is about to happen...
可是一件久违的大事
..for an age.
即将发生
Entmoot.
树形人大会
'Tis a gathering.
是一次聚会
A gathering of what?
什么聚会
Beech. Oak.
山毛样 橡树
Chestnut. Ash.
楼树 折杨树
Good. Good. Good.
很好 很好
Many have come.
来了不少
Now we must decide if the Ents...
现在必须决定
...Will go to war.
我们是否投入战争
Move back! Move to the caves!
回去 回到洞里去
-Keep moving. -Quickly now.
一回到酒里去 一大家快点
Farmers, farriers, stable boys.
农夫 马夫 还有蹄铁工
These are no soldiers.
不是打仗的材料
-Most have seen too many winters. -Or too few.
一他们要么岁数太大 -要么太小
Look at them. They're frightened.
你瞧他们 都吓坏了
You can see it in their eyes.
从眼神能看出来
Then I shall die as one of them!
那我就和他们一起去死
Let him go, lad.
让他去吧
Let him be.
别管他
Every villager able to wield a sword has been sent to the armoury.
所有能持剑的村民 全部都拿起了武器
My lord?
尊敬的国王
Who am I, Gamling?
我是谁 加姆林
You are our king, sire.
你是我们的国王 陛下
And do you trust your king?
你相信国王吗
Your men, my lord...
请您放心 无论陛下去哪儿
...Will follow you to whatever end.
我们都会永远跟随您
To whatever end.
无论去哪儿
Where is the horse and the rider?
我的千军万马呢
Where is the horn that was blowing?
怎么听不见距亮的号角
They have passed like rain on the mountains.
它们像雨落深山般消失
Like wind in the meadow.
又像吹过草原的疾风
The days have gone down in the West...
那灿烂而辉煌的过去
... behind the hills...
犹如太阳掉入了
..into Shadow.
西山背后的黑暗
How did it come to this?
怎么会变成这样
Move! Move to the outer wall.
动作快些 上外城墙
Give me your sword.
把剑给我
What is your name?
你叫什么名字?
Haleth, son of Hama, my lord.
哈里迪 哈玛的儿子
The men are saying we will not live out the night.
我的大王 有人说 我们今夜难逃一死
They say that it is hopeless.
还说我们没有希望
This is a good sword.
这是把好剑
Haleth, son of Hama...
哈里迪 哈玛的儿子
.. there is always hope.
希望永远存在
We have trusted you this far. You have not led us astray.
我们相信你 你没有素负我们的期望
Forgive me.
原谅我吧
l was wrong to despair.
我不该陷入绝望
We had time, I'd get this adjusted.
如果有了时间我就把这玩意改改
It's a little tight across the chest.
胸部有些紧
That is no Orc horn.
那不是半兽人的号角
Send for the king.
去叫国王
-Open the gate! -Open up the gate!
-打开城门
How is this possible?
这怎么可能
I bring word from Elrond of Rivendell.
瑞文戴尔的精灵王让我给国王带话
An alliance once existed between Elves and Men.
我们精灵与人类曾经是盟友
Long ago we fought and died together.
我们曾经同生共死
We come to honor that allegiance.
我们为盟友的名誉而来
You are most welcome.
你能来真是太好了
We are proud to fight alongside Men once more.
再次与人类并肩战斗是我们的骄傲
You could have picked a better spot.
你应该选个更好的地方
Well, lad, whatever luck you live by, let's hope it lasts the night.
伙计 尽管你福星高照 但今晚不可大意
Your friends are with you, Aragorn.
你的朋友和你在一起 阿拉贡
Let's hope they last the night.
那今天晚上都小心点
-What's happening out there? -Shall 1 describe it to you?
-外面出什么事了 -金勇 你想知道吗
Or would you like me to find you a box?
你站在箱子上自己看吧
So it begins.
战斗开始了
Did they hit anything?
他们射中没有?
Give them a volley.
命令放箭
-Fire!
一放射 一放生
Send them to me! Come on!
让他们来吧 来吧
Good!
好吧
Swords! Swords!
来呀 把他们了砍下去
Legolas! Two already!
莱戈拉斯 我报销两个
I'm on 17!
我已经十七个了
I'll have no pointy-ear outscoring me!
我可不能输给尖耳采的
Nineteen!
十九
Merry.
梅里
We have just agreed.
我们已经达成了一致
Yes?
是吗
[ have told your names to the Entmoot...
我向大会通报了你们的名字
..and we have agreed...
大会一致认定
.. you are not Orcs.
你们不是半兽人
Well, that's good news.
这是个好消息
And what about Saruman? Have you come to a decision about him?
那萨重曼呢? 你们做出了有关他的决定吗
Now, don't be hasty, Master Meriadoc.
别太性和急 先生们
Hasty?
性急?
Our friends are out there.
我的朋友们正在作战
They need our help. They cannot fight this war on their own.
他们需要我们帮助 他们自己无法赢得战争
War? Yes.
战争? 对 是的
It affects us all.
对大家都有影响
But you must understand, young Hobbit...
你们必须明白 起比特小伙子
..it takes a long time...
我们讲话
..to say anything in Old Entish...
从来都是慢吞吞的
...and we never say anything...
要么不说
...Unless it is worth taking...
要么就捡最重要的
...a long time to say.
慢慢道来
Seventeen! Eighteen!
十七 十八
Nineteen!
十九
Twenty!
二十
Twenty-one!
二十一
Causeway!
及准放箭 不能让他们攻上来
Is this it?
就这些吗?
Is this is all you can conjure, Saruman?
这就是你全部的能耐吗 萨曾曼
Brace the gate!
守住城门
Hold them! Stand firm!
镇静 坚持住
Aragorn!
阿拉贡
The Ents cannot hold back this storm.
我们阻止不了这场风暴
We must weather such things as we have always done.
我们只能一如既往地选择忍耐
How can that be your decision?!
你们怎么能做出这种决定
But you're part of this world!
可是你们是世界的一部分
Aren't you?!
不是吗
You must help. Please.
你必须参战
You must do something.
求你了 你一定要想办法
You are young and brave, Master Merry.
你们年轻无时 梅里先生
But your part in this tale is over.
但你们的角色已经演完了
Go back to your home.
该回家了
Maybe Treebeard's right.
也许树胡说得对
We don't belong here, Merry.
我们不属于这里
It's too big for us.
我们太各小了
What can we do in the end?
我们能做什么
We've got the Shire.
我们有有槛尔国
Maybe we should go home.
我们真该回家了
The fires of Isengard will spread...
战火将会蔓延开来
...and the woods of Tuckborough and Buckland will burn.
夏尔国很快也会变成战场
And...
最后
And all that was once green and good in this world will be gone.
和和平与善良将从世界上永远消失
There won't be a Shire, Pippin.
夏尔国同样不能幸免
Aragorn!
阿拉贡
Fall back to the Keep!
让你的人撤退回城堡
Get your men out of there!
叫他们撤退
Haldir!
哈尔达
What are you doing? What are you stopping for?
=- 快撤 -你们干什么 为什么停下
Haldir!
哈尔达
Brace the gate!
守住城门
Hold them!
守住
To the gate. Draw your swords!
披剑 快去城门
Make way!
快走
We cannot hold much longer!
我们快守不住了
-Hold them! -How long do you need?
- 项住 一要多长时间?
As long as you can give me.
越长越好
Timbers!
拿圆木来
Brace the gate!
守住城门
It's a long way.
距离太远了
Toss me.
那你可以把我扔过去
-What? -! cannot jump the distance!
-什么 -你快点扔吧
You'll have to toss me!
我过不去
Don't tell the Elf.
别告诉精灵
Not a word.
我不会说的
Shore up the door!
加固城门
-Make way! -Follow me to the barricade.
-内开 -大家跟我来
Watch our backs!
小心
-Throw another one over here! -Higher!
- 再搬一根过来 -高一些
Hold fast the gate!
城门守不住了
Gimli! Aragorn! Get out of there!
金雳 阿拉贡 马上撤退
Aragorn!
阿拉贡
Pull everybody back.
全体撤《回城堡
Pull them back.
让大家投回
Fall back!
撤退
They have broken through!
他们打进来了
The castle is breached. Retreat!
外城已经失守 快撤退
-Fall back! -Retreat!
- 撤退 -快 进去
Hurry! Inside. Get them inside!
让他们进去 快
Into the Keep!
退回城堡
I will leave you at the western borders of the forest.
我会在森林的西部边界和你们分手
You can make your way north to your homeland from there.
你们从那里往北就可以回家了
Wait! Stop!
等等 站住
Stop!
站住
Turn around.
向后转
-Turn around. Take us south. -South?
一向后转 带我们向南 - 向南?
But that will lead you past Isengard.
那是艾竹格的方向
Yes. Exactly.
是的 你说的没错
If we go south, we can slip past Saruman unnoticed.
坦南走就可以躲开萨曾曼的防线
The closer we are to danger, the farther we are from harm.
你知道吗越是危险的地方就越安全
It's the last thing he'll expect.
这是他完全想不到的
That doesn't make sense to me.
我可不那样看
But then...
不过
.. you are very small.
你们这么矮小
South it is, then.
那就朝南走吧
Hold on, little Shirelings.
抓紧我 夏尔国的小矮人
I always like going south.
我也喜欢朝南走
Somehow it feels like going downhill.
那毕竟是下山的方向
Are you mad? We'll be caught.
你疯了吗 我们会被抓住
No, we won't.
不 不会的
Not this time.
这次不会
Look!
瞧邮
Osgiliath burns!
奥斯吉力亚斯在燃烧
Mordor has come.
魔多开战了
The Ring will not save Gondor.
魔戒救不了刚铎
It has only the power to destroy.
它只有毁灭的力量
Please...
求你了
..let me go.
放我走吧
Hurry.
快
Faramir!
法拉米尔
You must let me go!
你一定要放我走
And those little family of field mice...
那几帘小田鼠经常叹上来
...that climb up sometimes, and they tickle me awfully.
让我感到奇痒无比
They're always trying to get somewhere where they....
它们总想找个地方
Creatures I had known from nut and acorn.
在他们种下之前我就认识他们了
I'm sorry, Treebeard.
对不起 树胡
They had voices of their own.
他们拥有各自的声音
Saruman.
萨重曼
A wizard should know better!
巫师不该砍伐我们
There is no curse in Elvish...
无论是在精灵的还是人类的世界
...Entish or the tongues of Men...
都找不到诅罗
...for this treachery.
这种背叛行径的语言
My business is with Isengard tonight...
今天晚上我要用巨石和岩石
...With rock and stone.
毁灭艾笠格
Yes.
太棒了
Come, my friends.
来吧 来吧 我的朋友们
The Ents are going to war.
树形人要参战了
It is likely...
也许这就是
..that we go to our doom.
我们的命运
Last march...
树形人的
...of the Ents.
最后进军
Faramir! Orcs have taken the eastern shore. Their numbers are too great.
法拉米尔 半兽人已经占领了 东海岸 他们数量太多
By nightfall we will be overrun.
傍晚时分我们就会被打败
Mr. Frodo?
佛罗多老他
It's calling to him, Sam. His Eye is almost on me.
是魔戒在召唤他 他的日光就要找到我了
Hold on, Mr. Frodo. You'll be all right.
坚持住 佛罗多老公 你不会有事的
Take them to my father.
带他们去见我父王
Tell him Faramir sends a mighty gift.
就说法拉米尔带回来 一件非凡的礼物
A weapon that will change our fortunes in this war.
一件能够改变我们战争命运的利器
Do you want to know what happened to Boromir?
你想知道博罗米尔是怎么死的吗
You want to know why your brother died?
你想知道他为什么会死吗
He tried to take the Ring from Frodo after swearing an oath to protect him!
他曾经发拆要保护佛罗多 后来又想从他手里夺取魔戒
He tried to kill him!
他想杀死他
The Ring drove your brother mad!
魔戒让你哥哥变成了疯子
Watch out!
当心
Mr. Frodo?
佛罗多老他
They're here.
来了
They've come.
他们来了
Stay here. Keep out of sight.
待在这儿 别让他看见
Take cover!
快隐蔬
The fortress is taken.
城堡已被攻陷
It is over.
我们失败了
You said this fortress would never fall while your men defend it.
你说过只要还剩一个人就不会失败
They still defend it. They have died defending it.
他们还在战斗 他们会战斗到底的
They're breaking in!
他们打进来了
They're past the door!
他们攻进了城门
Is there no other way for the women and children to get out of the caves?
还有其它出口让女人孩子逃生吗
Is there no other way?
还有出口吗
There is one passage. It leads into the mountains.
有一条小路通往深山老林
But they will not get far. The Uruk-hai are too many.
可他们逃不了多远 强兽人太多了
Tell the women and children to make for the mountain pass.
让女人和孩子从小路迷走
-And barricade the entrance! -So much death.
一快去把进口堵上 一血流成河
What can Men do against such reckless hate?
人类怎能抵挡这种刻骨的仇恨
Ride out with me.
我们冲出去
Ride out and meet them.
和他们决一死战
For death and glory.
为荣誉而战
For your people.
为了你的人民
The sun is rising.
太阳出来了
Look to my coming at first light on the fifth day.
当第5天的第一缕曙光出现
At dawn...
我就会回来
...l00k to the east.
注意黎明时的东方
Yes.
是的
The horn of Helm Hammerhand...
先王的号角
... Shall sound in the Deep...
将最后一次
...one last time.
在山谷吹响
Yes!
好的
Let this be the hour when we draw swords together.
让我们辐仇敌心并肩战斗
Fell deeds, awake.
那恶终于降临
Now for wrath...
该报仇了
...now for ruin and a red dawn.
为了贤灭 为了血红的黎明
Forth Eorlingas!
跟我冲啊
Gandalf.
甘道夫
Théoden King stands alone.
塞奥顿王孤掌难鸣
Not alone.
还有我在
Rohirrim!
罗罕的子民
. Eomer.
伊欧黑
To the king!
为国王而战
Yes!
好吧
A hit. A fine hit.
打得好
Break the dam!
炸开大坝
Release the river!
引入河水
Pippin! Hold on!
皮平 抓紧了
Hold on, little Hobbits.
抓紧 小需比特人
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿 佛罗多
It's me.
是我
It's your Sam.
是你的山姆
Don't you know your Sam?
你不认识山姆了?
I can't do this, Sam.
我坚持不住 山姆
I know.
我知道
It's all wrong.
这是个错误
By rights, we shouldn't even be here.
实际上我们本不该来这儿
But we are.
可我们来了
It's like in the great stories, Mr. Frodo.
就像在古老的传说中
The ones that really mattered.
那些真正的传说
Full of darkness and danger they were.
里面笼罩着黑暗和危险
And sometimes you didn't want to know the end...
有时你甚至不想听到结尾
... because how could the end be happy?
怎么可能有幸福的结局呢
How could the world go back to the way it was...
当这么多的那恶发生以后
...when so much bad had happened?
世界怎么可能回到原先的状态呢
Victory!
胜利
We have victory!
我们胜利了
But in the end, it's only a passing thing...
不过说到底危险
... this shadow.
早晚都会过去
Even darkness must pass.
黑暗也会消失
A new day will come.
黎明终将到来
And when the sun shines, it will shine out the clearer.
当太阳再次升起的时候会更加明亮
Those were the stories that stayed with you...
这些有意义的传说
... that meant something.
都在你的心里
Even if you were too small to understand why.
即使你年龄太小还无法理解
But I think, Mr. Frodo, do understand.
可是我觉得 佛罗多老爷我能明白
{ know now.
我现在能理解
Folk in those stories...
传说中的人物
...had lots of chances of turning back, only they didn't.
都有机会回头 但是他们不肯
They kept going...
他们一直问前
... because they were holding on to something.
因为他们都有自己的信念
What are we holding on to, Sam?
我们的信念是什么 山姆
That there's some good in this world, Mr. Frodo.
我们相信这个世界并韭不可救药
And it's worth fighting for.
值得我们为之战斗
I think at last we understand one another, Frodo Baggins.
我想我们终于互相了解了 佛罗多“' 巴金斯
You know the laws of our country, the laws of your father.
你很清楚我国的法委 你父王的法委
If you let them go, your life will be forfeit.
如果你放他们走 你就会被处死
Then it is forfeit.
那就处死我吧
Release them.
放了他们
Sauron's wrath will be terrible, his retribution swift.
索伦复仇将会更加残酷 而且迅狸异常
The battle for Helm's Deep is over.
炙尔穆斯保卫战已经结束
The battle for Middle-earth is about to begin.
中土之战即将开始
All our hopes now lie with two little Hobbits...
所有希望寄托在两位身处异乡的
... somewhere in the wilderness.
昨比特人身上
l wonder if we'll ever be put into songs or tales.
不知人们会不会把我们 也写进歌曲或传说
What?
什么
l wonder if people will ever say, "Let's hear about Frodo and the Ring."
不知人们会不会说 我们要听佛罗多和魔戒的故事
And they'll say, "Yes! That's one of my favorite stories."
他们会说 没错 那是我最喜欢的故事
"Frodo was really courageous, wasn't he, Dad?"
佛罗多非常勇敢 对吗 爸爸?
"Yes, my boy.
是的 我的儿子
The most famousest of Hobbits. And that's saying a lot."
他是最著名的蝴比特人 人们经常提起他
Well, you've left out one of the chief characters:
你漏掉了最主要的角色
"Samwise the Brave."
勇士山姆怀斯
l want to hear more about Sam.
我更想听山姆的故事
Frodo wouldn't have got far without Sam.
没有山姆就没有佛罗多
Now, Mr. Frodo, you shouldn't make fun. was being serious.
好了 佛罗多老爷 别开玩笑了 我可是认真的
So was I.
我也是
"Samwise the Brave."
勇士山姆怀斯
Sméagol?
斯米格?
We're not going to wait for you. Come on.
我们不等你了 快点
Master.
是主人
Master looks after us.
主人会照顾我的
Master wouldn't hurt us.
主人他不会伤害我
Master broke his promise.
主人违背了故言
Don't ask Sméagol.
斯米格不听你的
Poor, poor Sméagol.
可怜的斯米格
Master betrayed us.
主人他出卖了我们
Wicked. Tricksy. False.
他狼谁 他政恶 虚伪
We ought to wring his filthy little neck.
我们应该反断他的臭脖子
Kill him! Kill him!
杀了他 杀了他
Kill them both!
杀了他们两个
And then we take the precious...
然后夺回宝贝
...and we be the master!
我们就是主人了
But the fat Hobbit, he knows.
可是那个胖子他知道我们的打算
Eyes always watching.
他紧紧地采着我
Then we stabs them out.
那就挖出他的眼睛
Put out his eyeses and make him crawl.
让他也在地上中行
Yes. Yes. Yes.
好了 对呀
Kill them both.
杀死他们俩
It's too risky. It's too risky.
太和危险了不行 这太危险了
Where is he? Where has he gone?
他在哪儿 他去哪儿了
-Hey, Gollum! Where are you? -Sméagol?
一咕噜 你在哪儿 一斯米格
We could let her do it.
我们可以让她来干
Yes, precious, she could.
是的 亲爱的 她能行
Come on, Hobbits. Long ways to go yet.
来吧 霍比特人 路还远着呢
Sméagol will show you the way.
斯米格会给你们带路的
Follow me.
跟我来吧